SARATHA PREETHI GOPALAKRISHNAN

CONTACT



Southend-on-sea, Essex SS2 6FG



07442120295



sarathapreethi21@gmail.com

CORE QUALIFICATIONS

- Agile Methodologies
- Defect/Bug Tracking
- Functional Testing
- Continuous Testing CI/CD pipeline
- Test Strategies & Coverages
- Troubleshoot testing problems
- Behavioral driven framework
- Scripting & Documentation
- Avid Learning & Adaptable to ideas
- UI Testing
- Automated Test Systems
- Multi-tasking & leadership skills
- Test Planning, Test Estimation,
- Test Strategy, Test Cases Design,
- Test Environment Setup, Test Data Setup,
- Defect Management & Configuration Management
- Scrum frameworks
- Kanban frameworks
- Manual test case preparation
- Defect monitoring
- Cross-platform testing
- Manual Testing,
- Unit Testing, Usability Testing,
- Smoke Testing, Integration Testing,
- Regression Testing
- Web Application testing,
- Git Hub, JMeter

Dedicated Software Tester experienced with diverse software products. Solid history in both manual and automated testing. Attentive to details and careful to check software in detail to root out errors and performance issues. Demonstrated success in grey, white and black box testing. Writes and understands test cases, creates test plans and identifies use cases. Brings comprehensive understanding of full software development lifecycle.

EXPERIENCE

September 2020 - September 2022

Software Test Specialist LTI Mindtree, Chennai

- A centralized online application that delivers applications, along with supporting documents, to residency programs
- Wrote detailed test scenarios and cases, accurately logging errors and defects in comprehensive test reports.
- Used Agile methodologies to aid team delivery of effective, quality software solutions.
- Carried out automated and manual test execution, delivering relevant test coverage.
- NOTABLE ACCOMPLISHMENTS
- Ensured maximum test coverage by creating scalable test cases
- Provided support to teams targeting 100% Resilience, Availability, and Automation
- Consistently maintained Defect Rejections within 5%
- Exceeded 95% in Defect Removal Efficiency and increased the effectiveness of testing
- Successfully delivered projects with 0% defect leakage to Production
- Volunteered to deliver consistent customer support and Improve workplace productivity by contributing to creating the perfect knowledge base articles
- Headed up gaining expertise in UI, API automation, and nonfunctional performance testing and demonstrated adaptability to work in a flexible environment
- Prioritised bugs through focused data collection and analysis, driving continual innovation.

June 2018 - August 2020

Senior Test Engineer LTI Mindtree, Chennai

- A centralized financial interest repository Angular JS Application
- Testing frameworks JMeter, Protractor, & Jasmine (JavaScript testing framework)
- Tools used Atom, Visual Studio, Sauce Labs, Bamboo, Qtest, JIRA, AWS, Invision app
- API Testing Postman Tools
- Key Result Areas
- Managed complete functional and performance testing; ensured 100% on-time and in-quality deliverables
- Supported QA test lead in project testing estimation and scheduling

- Key player in client interactions with a strong business understanding
- Performed Accessibility testing in Lighthouse (Chrome Add-on), Cross-browser testing (Sauce Labs), UX/component testing, Prototype testing
- Applied business and functional knowledge including testing standards, guidelines, and testing methodology to meet the overall test objectives

January 2016 - November 2017

Functional Tester 3 EDGE SOLUTIONS, Chennai

- Functional testing in Web application ~ Test Planning ~ Defects Tracking
- Key project executed
- Clinical Research Domain | Team Size: 5 | Client: Serena Groups
- Clinical Trials Management System, Testing frameworks Functional testing in Web-based applications using
- Tools used Jira and MS Office

EDUCATION

2015

Bachelor of Engineering Electronics, and Communications New Prince Shri Bhavani College of Engineering

• Electronics and Communication Graduate